Kishan Narotam



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (Electrical) Information

University of the Witwatersrand Johannesburg, South Africa 2019

IEB National Senior Certificate with Advanced Programme Mathematics

St John's College Johannesburg, South Africa 2012

INDUSTRIES

Logistics & Market Research

Education & Training

ICT (Information & Communication Technologies)

Engineering

Insurance

Banking

Gender · Male

Disability · None

Race · Indian

Languages · English

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Information (**Electrical**) **Engineer** currently employed as an *Associate Consultant* at *IQbusiness*, with a drive in the corporate environment and the desire to apply himself to his maximum potential. Having worked on various projects where his role ranged from lead engineer to a business analyst and to a data analyst, Kishan's approach to work is methodical and analytical. The execution of the task is planned accordingly, to complete all objectives in the most efficient and successful manner so that the maximum value can be added.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Consultant · IQbusiness | Johannesburg, South Africa # 29/01/2020 - Current

Responsibilities: Kishan was part of the BasIQs programme within IQbusiness. He has worked as a business analyst on an internal project as well as an external project. He has successfully performed the role of a Data Analyst for Genex Insights and worked as an analyst within Absa's model risk space that would lead to a tactical journey in 2021.

Teaching Assistant · University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa

Responsibilities: Kishan was required to help run, execute and demonstrate laboratories and tutorials. In doing so he required extensive knowledge of C++, SFML, GitHub and Git collaboration. Throughout the course, Kishan assisted the students in a variety of ways relating to their work.

Intern · Liberty Life Head Office | Johannesburg, South Africa

07/2017

28/11/2016 - 18/01/2017

06/05/2016 - 17/06/2016

Responsibilities: Kishan worked in the IT department of the company assisting the HOD in various projects. The projects tasked to Kishan ranged from data collection, database management, network mapping, system analysis, C++ and VBA programming and Excel programming.

Intern · MICROS South Africa (Pty) Ltd | Johannesburg, South Africa # 26/06/2015 - 03/07/2015

Responsibilities: Kishan was challenged with analysing C# code for an ongoing project and was tasked with converting the project into C++. Following this, Kishan had to design and implement a basic user interface for the analysed code.

Kishan Narotam

</> TOOLKIT

Software Development

MATLAB · C++ · Java · HTML · CSS · NodeJS · Assembly · Python

Project Management

Scrum · Kanban · MS Project · Trello · Test Driven Development

Databases

MySQL · MS Access

Continuous Integration

Gil

Analysis

MS Excel · Power BI · Tableau

Technical Writing

MS Word \cdot MS PowerPoint \cdot MS Outlook \cdot MS Visio \cdot LaTeX

Graphical Editing

Adobe Premiere Pro

CERTIFICATES

IBM (Coursera)

Data Science Foundations Specialization · 08 December 2020

Databases and SQL for Data Science · 08 December 2020

Python for Data Science and AI · 01 December 2020 Data Science Methodology · 20 November 2020 Tools for Data Science · 17 November 2020 Data Science Orientation · 10 November 2020

Microsoft

MTA: Database Fundamentals: Certificate 2020 · 15 September 2020

ICAgile

ICAgile Certified Professional · 04 May 2020

Tableau

Tableau Author · 29 May 2020 Tableau Consumer · 26 May 2020

IQbusiness

UX Design Bootcamp · 21 August 2020

UiPath Academy

RPA Business Analyst Foundation · 12 May 2020 RPA Starter Training · 03 March 2020

ECDL Foundation

International Computer Driving Licence (ICDL) · 04 May 2012



ONLINE PROFILE

in /in/kishan-y-narotam/

/ /KNarotam

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Project Overview: The model risk architecture and processes for credit regulatory reporting are sub-optimal in terms of business efficiencies being realised across the value chain. The project team developed a target state architecture and roadmap identifying opportunities for unlocking sustainable efficiency. Subsequently, the project team took the various stakeholders through various roadshow presentations to gain valuable buy-in on the identified opportunities and created a project charter for the initiatives.

Responsibilities: Kishan was an analyst supporting the team in a variety of manners. In the first phase of the project, Kishan defined various role profiles for stakeholders in the model risk space, mapped out necessary frameworks, policies and standards for a clearer understanding. In the subsequent phase, Kishan assisted in creating a project charter for a tactical journey that will occur in 2021, identifying benefits and associated metrics.

Project Overview: The project involved working on the MultiChoice Africa account within the CX team, where the data's integrity had to be investigated and monitored. In conjunction to this assisting the team in applying various methodologies that would allow the team to become more proactive in handling the account, and to improve relationships between the MultiChoice Africa and Genex Insights.

Responsibilities: Kishan was placed as a Data Analyst within the Genex Insights' CX team initially investigating a data discrepancy issue, utilising the Genex Insights VOC platform to assist with data retrieval, mapping & managing for MultiChoice Africa. Kishan also updated & created new dashboard views for surveys that had existed & were introduced respectively. Kishan's understanding of the platform gave him the opportunity to train new MultiChoice members on using the platform, while handling queries daily.

Business Analyst · IAM AfricaAccess | CSO Testing Proposal Absa Group Limited | Johannesburg, South Africa # 30/01/2020 - 04/02/2020

Lead Engineer · Design of a Thermally Controlled System for Medications University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa ## 17/09/2019 - 25/10/2019

Co-Lead Engineer · Image Compression Based on Non-Parametric Sampling in Noisy Environments

University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa ### 01/07/2019 - 11/09/2019

For a detailed view of all certificates; testimonials; projects and subsequent responsibilities can be found on CV tab of my website or at the link below. https://knarotam.github.io/Pages/CV/CV.html